the
I'll
of
Ste
the ground ball room
so we've got a good time life
yeah
school
we come into this world
mean clue innate abilities to learn to
interact
with you other ascension be what
pressured to interact with other people
by writing little messages to them
be a real pain
and that's how we interact with
computers it's much easier just to talk
to them
is just so much easier here if the
computers can understand what we think
and polite you need really good speech
recognition
the first speech recognition system was
developed by Bell Laboratories in 1952
it can only recognize numbers spoken by
one person
in the nineteen seventies karnicki
nanking out harpy system which was able
to recognize over 1,000 words
and could recognize different
pronunciations the same word
tomato Moda speech recognition continued
eighties the introduction hidden Markov
model which used in more mathematical
approach to analyzing sound waves
and led to many the breakthroughs we
have today you're taking in very raw
audio waveforms
like you got from mike von on your phone
or whatever
we chop it into small pieces price
to identify which phoneme West spoken
in that loss d-sub speech for phoneme is
the kind of primitive unit for
expressing
were ha I
home I'll tell and Mandy Moore won a
stage those together into
likely words like Palo Alto speech
recognition
today is quite good in transcribing what
you've said what's the weather like to
pick a
you can talk about troubles you can talk
about your contacts
like where can I get pizza journalistic
how tall is Apple tower
our we've made tremendous improvements
very quickly
who is the twenty first president to the
United States Chester and there was a
totedaho
where's he from years ago you had to be
an engineer in Iraq with computers
I'll I mean today everybody can interact
1p know if
pill in the infancy is the understanding
we need a far more sophisticated
language understanding model
understands what the standards means
missed in a very long way from having
did 0 the
our ability to use language in wanted
the in home
chins it's one of the things
company from one generation to another
figuring out
about how the system language worms you
know that seems like a really easy
problems
me one it's really hard but that every
baby has managed by the time they're
years old %uh %um to our yell
I'll man's
language is extremely complex and
sophisticated from the semantics irony
strong accent facial expressions human
emotion is at Sparta
how we communicate humor I have to be
careful not to offend the diameter
language has so many different layers
and that's why it's such a difficult
problem
the present the human brain and the
learning outcomes in human brains
far far better things I language
understanding and this to a better
package
to whether or not we replicate exactly
with the brain does
I to understand language and to
understand speech
is still a questions
for many many years 0 we believe
good neural network should work better
Rooney
dumb existing technology was basically
just take a look at home
and then in 2009 to my students
with little input from me goaded
working better own first time it just
went a little bit better but then it was
obvious that this could be developed
somewhat much better
the brain has these millions in your
arms all computing power
and all the knowledge in the brain
within the strength to the connection
between your
what I mean by neural net is something
mince
simulating a conventional computer but
is designed to work
in very very rough in the same way as
the bread
so until quite recently people go
speeches by
and engineering they look good sign
waving
did for reanalysis I may try to figure
out what features should we feed to the
pattern recognition system
nothing on your own networks as they
learn their own features in particular
they can on features and then they can
and features a few chosen and features a
pink jersey features
my sleep with huge improvement in speed
range
but you can also use them for language
understanding past
and the way you do this is you represent
words
be in very high-dimensional spaces we
can now deal with analogies
where would his representatives and
mister numbers so for example if i take
me
mister hundred-numbers the represents
patterns
and I subtract from it brings and I had
to indigent
and if I look at the numbers I'll the
closest thing
is unlisted numbers eruptions romel for
by first converting went into these
numbers using your own anymore
with you can actually do this and
logical reasoning
the new I predict that in the next five
years
would come clean these big did you know
that works with the new learning
algorithms
again to give us much meddling regions
when we started out we thought that
things like chap
for nap now ranks or our lodging
those are going to be the things that
were really hard on back hard I mean we
can end up with the machine actually can
do chats as well as the ground after
camp lejeune the things that we thought
were gonna be easy
for computer system like understanding
language
things have turned out to be incredibly
hard I can't even imagine
a though we've done it the moment might
get just because there are so many
is this puzzled that around songs both
from a science my nephew on as well as
come from a technical
nationwide there's a lot of unknowns
those are the great revolution sir
not just when been a little with what we
already know about when we discover
something completely new and unexpected
I think once you kind ever in the
ballpark give him another
that will be the pretty remarkable
the I'll
ok